第 3 章：Cat、caught、cut。A 等于 ah，O 等于 aw，U 等于 uh。在打好
Chapter 3. Cat, caught, cut. A equals ah, O equals ah, U equals uh. After laying our
语调和连读的基础后，我们终于开始精炼你的
foundation with intonation and liaisons, here we finally begin to refine your
我们现在要研究 ah、ah 和 uh 之间的区别，以及
pronunciation. We're now going to work on the differences between ah, ah, and uh, as
还包括 O、A 和 eh。先从 /ah/ 音开始。/ah/ 音虽然不是
well as O, A, and eh. Let's start out with the ah sound. The ah sound. Although not a
对耳朵来说很有辨识度，也很典型地美式。
common sound, A is very distinctive to the ear and is typically American. In the
在练习段落里，这个声音出现五次。正如它的音标所示，A
practice paragraph, this sound occurs five times. As its phonetic symbol indicates, A
是 A 和 E 的组合。要发这个音，下巴往下放，就像准备发 A，
is a combination of A and E. To pronounce it, drop your jaw down as if you're going
然后从那个位置，试着说E。最后的声音不是两个
to say A, but then from that position, try to say E. The final sound is not two
分开的两个元音，而是二者结合后的最终结果。它非常接近
separate vowels, but rather the end result of the combination. It's very close to the
山羊叫声。MAAH！现在试几次：AW、AA、AW、AA。如果你发现
sound that a goat makes. MAAH! Try it a few times now. AW, AA, AW, AA. If you find
yourself getting too nasal with AA, pinch your nose as you say it. If cat turns into
你需要把声音从鼻腔拉出来，放到喉咙里。
can't, you need to pull the sound out of your nose and down into your throat. Note,
寻找 AA 音时，你可能会以为 down 或 sound 这类词里有
as you look for the AA sound, you might think that words like down or sound have
这个双元音可以试着用 A 加 O，或 OU 来发。这样 down 就会
an AA in them. For this diphthong, try A plus O, or OU. This way, down would be
写成 da-own。不过，因为它是组合音，所以不包括在
written da-own. Because it's a combined sound, however, it's not included in the
cat 这一类。AH 音。AH 音出现得更频繁。
cat category. The AH sound. The AH sound occurs a little more frequently. You'll
你会在练习中找到十个这样的声音。
find ten such sounds in the exercise. To pronounce AH, relax your tongue and drop
下巴尽量往下放。事实上，把手放在
your jaw as far down as it'll go. As a matter of fact, put your hand under your
下巴下面，说 ma-pa-ta-sa。嘴巴张开时，下巴应该把你的手往下推。
chin and say ma-pa-ta-sa. Your hand should be pushed down by your jaw as it opens.
记住，这是医生想看你喉咙时让你发出的声音，所以要张开
Remember, it's the sound you make when the doctor wants to see your throat, so open
嘴巴，下巴下放。schwa 音。最后是 schwa，也是最常见的声音
it up and drop your jaw. The schwa sound. Last is the schwa, the most common sound
在美式英语中。当你练习段落时，取决于语速、
in American English. When you work on a practice paragraph, depending on how fast
你说话时连读有多顺、语调有多强，
you speak, how smoothly you make liaisons, how strong your intonation is, and how
以及你让发音放松到什么程度，你会找到 50 到 75 个 schwa。拼写并不能
much you relax your sounds, you'll find from 50 to 75 schwas. Spelling doesn't
帮助识别它，因为它可以表现为任意一个元音，或元音组合的一部分。
help identify it because it can appear as any one of the vowels or a combination of
它是一个中性元音 uh。它通常出现在非重读音节里，虽然
them. It's a neutral vowel sound, uh. It's usually in an unstressed syllable, though
它也可以被重读。每当你找到一个可以划掉、且
it can be stressed as well. Whenever you find a vowel that can be crossed out and
它的缺失不会改变这个词的发音，你可能已经
its absence wouldn't change the pronunciation of the word, you've probably
找到的很可能就是 schwa。Photography。两个撇号标出了中性元音的
found a schwa. Photography. The two apostrophes show the location of the
不过，因为它太常见了，错误地发
neutral vowel sounds. Because it's so common, however, the wrong pronunciation
哪怕其他方面都很好，这一个小音发错也会让你的口音很重。
of this one little sound can leave your speech strongly accented, even if you
其他方面都美式化了。注意，有些词典会使用两种不同的书写符号，
Americanized everything else. Note, some dictionaries use two different written
倒写的 E 和倒写的 V；我们只使用第一个。
symbols, the upside-down E and the upside-down V, We're only going to use the first
一个可以表示不发音或中性；schwa 是中性的，但不是无声的。相比之下，
one silent or neutral a schwa is neutral, but it's not silent By comparison the
词尾不发音的 e 是发音提示，但它本身不读出来。
silent e at the end of a word is a signal for pronunciation, but it's not pronounced
Code 读作 code；词尾 e 提醒你读 o。如果去掉 e，就成了 cod。
itself Code is code the e tells you to say an o if you leave the e off you have cod
另一方面，schwa 是中性的，但它是一个实际的声音。比如
The schwa on the other hand is neutral, but it's an actual sound uh For example
你也可以把 photography 写成 fa ta gra fee。因为它是中性音，
you could also write photography as fa ta gra fee Because it's a neutral sound, the
虽然 schwa 没有任何鲜明特征，但它是最常见的声音。
schwa doesn't have any distinctive characteristics, yet it is the most common
要发英语里的 uh 音，把手放在横膈膜上。
sound in the English language. To make the uh sound, put your hand on your diaphragm
推一下，让一声闷哼自然出来。不要移动下巴、舌头或嘴唇。
and push until a grunt escapes. Don't move your jaw, tongue, or lips. Just allow the
只让声音流过声带，应该听起来像 uh。
sound to flow past your vocal cords. It should sound like uh. Once you master this
掌握这个音之后，can 和 can't 也会更容易发准。
sound, you will have an even easier time with pronouncing can and can't. In a
在句子中，can't 听起来仍像 can't；但 can 会变成 kun，除非它在句中被重读为 can，
sentence, can't sounds like can't, But, can becomes kun unless it is stressed when
也就是 can：I can do it。I can't do it。元音图。接下来的
it is can. I can do it. I can't do it. Vowel chart. In the vowel chart that
四个角代表口腔中四个最极端的位置。
follows, the four corners represent the four most extreme positions of the mouth.
中间的格子代表最不极端的位置，也就是中性的 schwa。
The center box represents the least extreme position, the neutral schwa. For
这四个位置里，只移动嘴唇和下巴。舌头应该保持在
these four positions, only move your lips and jaw. Your tongue should stay in the
同一个位置，舌尖抵在下齿后方。第一，要发 beat，
same place, with the tip resting behind the bottom teeth. One to pronounce beat
发 beat 时，嘴唇应该向后拉，牙齿靠近。嘴巴
your lips should be drawn back, but your teeth should be close together Your mouth
嘴巴应该形成香蕉的形状。第二，发 boot 时，嘴唇应该完全
should form the shape of a banana Two to pronounce boot your lips should be fully
收圆，牙齿靠近。嘴巴应该形成
rounded and your teeth should be close together Your mouth should form the shape
Cheerio 的形状。第三，发 bought 时，从 boot 的口型直接把下巴
of a Cheerio Three to pronounce bought drop your jaw straight down from the boot
的位置直接放下下巴。嘴巴应该形成鸡蛋的形状。第四，发 bat 时，保持
position your mouth should form the shape of an egg Four, to pronounce bat, keep
下巴保持放低，嘴唇往后拉，试着同时发 ah 和 eh。
your jaw down, pull your lips back, and try to simultaneously say ah and eh. Your
嘴巴应该形成盒子的形状。注意，逐词发音会
mouth should form the shape of a box. Note, word-by-word pronunciation will be
不同于句子中单个声音的实际发音。That、than、as、at、and、have、
different than individual sounds within a sentence. That, than, as, at, and, have,
had、can 等词单独读时包含 eh 音，但它们是弱读词，
had, can, and so on contain eh sounds when they stand alone, but they are weak words
这些词在语流中会很快弱化。
that reduce quickly in speech.